Trevor DePew

New York, New York | tadepewmusic@gmail.com | (347) 374-1901 LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Software Engineer

Experienced in React and Python based programming with a background in Music Composition and Art. Possess strong skills in problem solving, pattern recognition, project leading, and design that help with developing well thought out applications. Able to ride a unicycle.

Technical Skills

Python, Flask, SQLite3, React, JavaScript, Ruby3, Rails 6, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Github, VSCode, Postman, SQL, R, Excel, Sibelius 7, Orchestral Score reading, Western Music Theory & Composition, Schenkerian Analysis

Technical Projects

Portfolio Website - Github

A single-page personal website to demonstrate skills and showcase projects

- Created a responsive layout using React and CSS which is able to be displayed on different devices and screen sizes.
- Employed accessibility best practices to account for screen readers and color blindness.
- Designed an environment which demonstrates personal style while adhering to common layout patterns to ensure ease of use.
- Used scalable components to allow for additional content without the need to rebuild the application.

TADLAB Mini - Github

A software synthesizer with the ability to connect to an external MIDI device.

- Using React and Tone is, created a software synthesizer with multiple oscillators allowing user to create different sounds.
- Built a user interface to recreate the layout of a modular hardware synthesizer using React components and vanilla CSS.
- Designed a frontend user interface with fully functionally and visually interesting controls which give visual feedback to the user.
- Implemented functionality to allow user input via computer keyboard or through the mouse.

Sequinzer-6001-2a - Github

A synthesizer sequencer built entirely from React using Tone.js

- Created a user interface with React components and CSS while focusing on ease of use.
- Used React states to control objects related to the HTML elements to connect frontend with Tone.js.
- Explored ways to iterate through user interface grid so there is a visual and audible representation of the sequencer's function.
- Created wireframe to map out the application's end goals providing a clear order of operations and plan for future development.

Experience

Arolla Piano Co.

New York, New York
Piano Technician

June 2019 - Jan 2020

- Provided piano tuning, regulation and repair services to an average of 10 clients a week using electronic and ear techniques with standard piano tuning and repair tools in order to bring their instrument to its designed specs, allowing it to sound its best, and resolve or prevent performance issues in client pianos.
- Maintained a database of clients as well as payment and invoicing tooling using Google Sheets, Xero invoicing, and Square payments in order keep track of client service records, payments, and future service needs.

 ROLI
 New York, New York

 Creator Support
 July 2017 - July 2018

- Designed and implemented a system to track and catalog product shipments and returns using Google Sheets and Google Docs significantly reducing the turnover period of returns from 5 weeks to 2 weeks and reducing lost shipments from 4% to 1%.
- Coordinated between Tech Support, Sales, Logistics, and Package Carriers in order to provide smooth transactions for customers by providing accurate updates using a custom cataloging system and reducing interdepartmental lead times from 5 to 2 business days.
- Created documentation and project description outlining the returns process and how it should continue to expand in order to provide a guideline for a future RMA system and returns department.
- Initiated and performed repairs of MIDI instruments in New York reducing the turnaround for faulty products within the US and Canada from 8 weeks to 2 weeks.

Education

Flatiron School
New York, New York
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

CUNY Brooklyn College
M.M. Music Composition

Brooklyn, New York
May 2019